Guide to the John McComb Architectural Drawings Finding Aid 1766-1829 PR 40
New-York Historical Society
- Residence, unidentified, 92622 (Box McComb Box 15, Item 258)
- Residence, unidentified ink, LC: "Bed Chamber Floor", 92621 (Box McComb Box 15, Item 252)
- Residence, unidentified, 92620 (Box McComb box 6, Item 103b verso)
- Residence, unidentified, 92619 (Box McComb box 6, Item 104)
- Residence, unidentified (vaults of) Coles House?, 92618 (Box McComb box 6, Item 103a recto)
- Residence, unidentified [attrib] Main floor plan (attrib), 92617 (Box McComb box 1, Item 19)
- Residence, unidentified [attrib], 92616 (Box McComb box 1, Item 017a)
- Residence, unidentified [attrib] Upper floor plan [attrib], 92615 (Box McComb box 1, Item 20)
- Residence, unidentified [attrib] Facade [attrib], 92614 (Box McComb box 1, Item 21)
- Residence, unidentified, 2 versions of façade, 92613 (Box McComb box 4, Item 071b verso)
- Residence, unidentified, semi-detached, 92612 (Box McComb box 1, Item 13)
- Rotunda plan, attributed, 92611 (Box McComb Box 17, Item 349)
- Roxalana Roxalana. graphite LC, 92610 (Box McComb box 2, Item 39)
- School, 92609 (Box McComb Box 15, Item 269)
- School, 92608 (Box McComb Box 15, Item 269b recto)
- Schuylkill River Bridge Frame of the Bridge over the River Schuylkill at Philadelphia, 92607 (Box McComb box 1, Item 9)
- Sessions House A View of the Sessions House for the County of Middlesex on Clerkenwall Green, 1782, Nov 1; 92606 (Box McComb box 1, Item 010a)
- Sewer, 92605 (Box McComb Box 12, Item 205a recto)
- Sewer ink, LC: "Section of a Sewer intended to be built wholly of Brick-", 92604 (Box McComb Box 12, Item 203)
- Sewer, (unidentified), 92603 (Box McComb Box 11, Item 199b verso)
- Sewer, attributed, 92602 (Box McComb Box 12, Item 202)
- Sewing machine, attributed, [1799]; 92601 (Box McComb Box 19, Item 379 verso)
- Shot Tower with flag, attrib. ink, LR "Sketch showing t", 92600 (Box McComb Box 21, Item 434)
- Sketch Design for an urn: attributed, 92599 (Box McComb Box 18, Item 365)
- Sketch [Eagle head and claw], 92598 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 301 recto)
- Sketch Four designs for urns: attributed, 92597 (Box McComb Box 18, Item 363)
- Sketch [Sketch of John Mc.Comb Jr. (cf. Waldo portrait)], 92596 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 301 verso)
- Sketch Two light brackets (for gas lights?): attributed, 92595 (Box McComb Box 18, Item 351)
- Sketch Design on enthemion, scroll and flowers: attributed, 92594 (Box McComb Box 18, Item 355)
- Sketch Design for Door frame: attributed, 92593 (Box McComb Box 18, Item 367)
- Sketch Designs for eight urns and one metal grille: attributed, 92592 (Box McComb Box 18, Item 359)
- Sketch Swags and a head: attributed, 92591 (Box McComb Box 18, Item 358)
- Sketch [swags of grapes with ribbons], 92590 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 327)
- Sketch A design for cornices of doors: attrib., 92589 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 324 verso)
- Sketch Stove in a niche: attributed, 92588 (Box McComb Box 18, Item 362)
- Sketch Two designs for mantels: attributed, 92587 (Box McComb Box 18, Item 360)
- Sketch Three designs for urns: attributed, 92586 (Box McComb Box 18, Item 364)
- Sketch Steps and railing and three designs for metal work: attributed, 92585 (Box McComb Box 18, Item 361)
- Sketch Circular doodles: attrib., 92584 (Box McComb Box 15, Item 260 verso)
- Sketch Scroll design: attrib., 92583 (Box McComb Box 18, Item 356)
- Sketch Designs for hanging candelabras: attributed, 92582 (Box McComb Box 18, Item 357)
- Sketch Drawing of a door with transom and a ceiling rosette: attributed, 92581 (Box McComb Box 18, Item 366)
- Sketch, ornament [Lyre, sunburst, olive branch, cloud], 92580 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 300)
- Sketches, Vitruvius Britannicus, [1809]; 92579 (Box McComb box 1, Item 23)
- St. John's Chapel, 1807; 92578 (Box McComb box 3, Item 50)
- St. John's Chapel, 1803; 92577 (Box Drawer 7, Item 53)
- St. John's Chapel [attrib.], 1807; 92576 (Box McComb box 3, Item 52)
- St. John's Chapel [attrib], 1807; 92575 (Box McComb box 3, Item 51)
- St. John's Chapel, attributed graphite, LC: [St. John's Chapel?], 92574 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 126)
- St. Johns Church Ink, LC-LR: "First Story windows for St. Johns Church", 92573 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 125)
- St. Johns Church [Canandaigua] [Gothic] graphite, MC-MR: "St. Johns church", 92572 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 302)
- St. Paul's Chapel ink, LC-LR: "Peir & Urn disigned for S.t Pauls church yard -", 92571 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 318)
- St. Paul's Chapel, monument, sculptural tablet Verso, ink, UL: "Monument", 92570 (Box McComb box 4, Item 67)
- St. Paul's steeple St. Paul's Steeple. Ink MC, 1794 ink MC; 92569 (Box McComb box 3, Item 61)
- St. Paul's steeple, [1794]; 92568 (Box McComb box 3, Item 62)
- St. Paul's steeple: attrib. pencil, ML: "from ground 143 feet", 92567 (Box McComb Box 21, Item 453 verso)
- St. Peter's Church Ink, LC: "Front-View of St. Peters Church with the intended Steeple", 92566 (Box McComb box 4, Item 70)
- St. Peter's Church, 92565 (Box McComb box 4, Item 069 verso)
- Stiles and Beach Farm map, 92564 (Box McComb Box 5, Item 86)
- Store/house on Water Street, 92563 (Box McComb box 3, Item 059b verso)
- Stove designed as a fluted column with urn on top: attributed, 92562 (Box McComb Box 17, Item 331)
- Study for gates and piers: attrib., 92561 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 308 recto)
- Study of Egyptian Temple ink, MC: "Egyptian Temple", 92560 (Box McComb Box 21, Item 451)
- Study of Pantheon, attrib. pencil, UR-MR: "From the Pantheon", 92559 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 307)
- Study of Temple of Vesta, attrib. pencil, UL-UR: "Frieze of the Temple of Vesta", 92558 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 305)
- Sugar Refinery, attrib., 92557 (Box McComb Box 20, Item 426)
- Summer House [attrib in pencil LL], 92556 (Box McComb box 1, Item 14)
- Table Table showing the number of feet vertical to each degree of elevation at 100' feet horizontal. Ink LL to LR., 92555 (Box McComb box 2, Item 31)
- The London Lying-in Hospital, 92554 (Box McComb box 1, Item 025a recto)
- Theater, graphite LL-LR, 92553 (Box McComb box 4, Item 74)
- Theater, pencil LL-LR, 92552 (Box McComb box 4, Item A74)
- Town house, unidentified ink, LC: "1st Story", 92551 (Box McComb Box 14, Item 239)
- Tract house ink, LC: "Nassau St.", 1825; 92550 (Box McComb Box 12, Item 212)
- Tudor window and door openings, attrib., 92549 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 306)
- Two story building with tower, unidentified, 92548 (Box McComb Box 20, Item 425)
- Two-masted square rigger, attrib., 92547 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 312 verso)
- Two-masted square rigger, attrib., 92546 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 312)
- Urn Urn in niche: attributed, 92545 (Box McComb Box 17, Item 338 verso)
- Urn, 92544 (Box McComb Box 17, Item 333)
- Vestibule pilasters, necking Necking at large for pilasters in vestibule, 92543 (Box McComb box 1, Item 024c)
- Volute ink, UC-UR: "Manner of dicribeing the Elliptical Volute", 92542 (Box McComb Box 20, Item 428)
- Volute ink, UL-UR: "P Nicholsons method of describing the Ionic Volute whole Height of Capitals 35M.", 92541 (Box McComb Box 20, Item 430)
- Volute ink, UL: "Taken fm P. Nicholsons Principals of Architecture", 92540 (Box McComb Box 20, Item 431)
- Volute ink, UL-UC: "Method of describing an angular Volute-", 92539 (Box McComb Box 20, Item 429)
- Wall Street Presbyterian Church Ink, LC: "Wall Street", 92538 (Box McComb Box 10, Item 164)
- Wall Street Presbyterian Church, 92537 (Box McComb Box 10, Item 167 recto)
- Wall Street Presbyterian Church, 92536 (Box McComb Box 10, Item 166a)
- Wall Street Presbyterian Church, 92535 (Box McComb Box 10, Item 166b)
- Wall Street Presbyterian Church, attributed, 92534 (Box McComb Box 10, Item 168a recto)
- Wall Street Presbyterian Church, attributed, [1823]; 92533 (Box McComb Box 10, Item 165)
- Wall Street Presbyterian Church, attributed, 1823; April 6: ink, LR; 92532 (Box McComb Box 10, Item 169)
- Wall Street Presbyterian Church, attributed, 92531 (Box McComb Box 10, Item 168b verso)
- Wall with Palladian opening, attributed, 92530 (Box McComb Box 19, Item 394)
- Washington Hall, [1809]; 92529 (Box McComb box 3, Item 043a)
- Washington Hall Ink, LR: " the Amity to the Merit", 1809; July 4; 92528 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 123)
- Washington Hall, 1809; July 4; 92527 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 121)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4; 92526 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118x recto)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4; 92525 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118q)
- Washington Hall, [1809]; 92524 (Box McComb box 3, Item 043b)
- Washington Hall Ink, UL-UR: "Frame & Sill for the front of the Rear Building at 1/2 Size Frame & Sill for the Front of Washington Hall at 1/2 Size", 1809, July 4; 92523 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118e)
- Washington Hall, 1809; July 4; 92522 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 120)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4; 92521 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118p)
- Washington Hall Ink, MC: "McCombs Drawings of Washington Hall 1809", 1809, July 4; 92520 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118)
- Washington Hall A design for the front elevation of Washington Hall to be built on Nassau and Spruce Sts.: attributed, 92519 (Box McComb Box 12, Item 211)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4; 92518 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118aa)
- Washington Hall Circular building: unidentified, plan and elevation, 1809, July 4; 92517 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118k verso)
- Washington Hall Ink, LL-LR: "Section of Stairs and Passage", 1809, July 4; 92516 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118j)
- Washington Hall Ink, LC-LR: "Washington Hall on Read Street-", 1809, July 4; 92515 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118l)
- Washington Hall Ink, LC: "as Executed", 1809, July 4; 92514 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118c)
- Washington Hall Ink, UC-UR: "Plan of framing Spring floor of Washington Hall-", 1809; July 4; 92513 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 122)
- Washington Hall Ink, LL-LR: "Plan of the first Floor of Washington Hall with the framing of the floor", 1809, July 4; 92512 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118t)
- Washington Hall graphite, ML-MC: "Chimney Top-full Size", 1809, July 4; 92511 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118a 1/2 verso)
- Washington Hall Roof framing plan [attrib.], 1809; July 4; 92510 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118a recto)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4; 92509 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118x1/2 verso)
- Washington Hall First and second floor plans, Reade Street portion, 1809, July 4; 92508 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118k recto)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4; 92507 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118z recto)
- Washington Hall Ink, LC: "Plan and Section of an Ice Vault for Washington Hall", 1809, July 4; 92506 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118u)
- Washington Hall Entrance design, interior [attrib.], 1809, July 4; 92505 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118)
- Washington Hall Ink, LC: "Sketch of the front of Washington Hall-", 1809, July 4; 92504 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118m)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4; 92503 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118h)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4; 92502 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118o)
- Washington Hall A design for the front elevation of Washington Hall not adopted [attrib.], [1809]; 92501 (Box McComb box 6, Item 119)
- Washington Hall Elevations, 1809, July 4; 92500 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118r)
- Washington Hall Ink, LC-LR: "First design for Washington Hall-", 1809, July 4; 92499 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118n)
- Washington Hall Ink, LC: "2c. Story of Washington Hall-", 1809, July 4; 92498 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118s)
- Washington Hall Ink, LL-LR: "Plan, of the Fire place in the N.E. back Room of Washington Hall - with a Section of the flue and Air Chamber", 1809, July 4; 92497 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118i)
- Washington Hall Column and entablature details [attrib.], 1809, July 4; 92496 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118)
- Washington Hall Ink, UL-UC: "Plan and Mouldings for Niche in the Hall-", 1809, July 4; 92495 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118bb)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4; 92494 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118v)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4; 92493 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118b)
- Washington Hall, [1809]; 92492 (Box McComb box 6, Item 117)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4; 92491 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118w)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4; 92490 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118z1/2 verso)
- Washington Hall, 1809, July 4; 92489 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118y)
- Washington Hall Entablature frieze details [attrib.], 1809, July 4; 92488 (Box McComb Box 7, Item 118g)
- Washington Hall [attrib in pencil LL], 92487 (Box McComb box 1, Item 18)
- Washington Hall [attrib.], 92486 (Box McComb box 6, Item 116)
- Washington Hall, attributed ink, UL-UC: "Hall - 87' - x 56'-", 92485 (Box McComb Box 19, Item 392)
- Washington Hall, Lydig's Lot, plan of, [1809]; 92484 (Box McComb box 3, Item 043c)
- Waterworks, attrib., 92483 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 324)
- Weathervane ornament, 92482 (Box McComb box 3, Item 058b verso)
- Wharf, attributed ink, LC: "Plan showing the 1st 2d 3d & 4th course of Timbers", 92481 (Box McComb Box 12, Item 210)
- Wharf, attributed, 92480 (Box McComb Box 12, Item 201)
- Window sill and sash, attrib., 92479 (Box McComb Box 15, Item 266 verso)
- Woman, unidentified, 92478 (Box McComb box 2, Item 38)